Guide to the Time Inc. Video Group Records 1934-1989 MS 3009-RG 41
New-York Historical Society
- Series VII.D. Time-Life Films: Special Projects Division: Television Book Records, 1934-1979; 25.5 Linear feet in 27 records cartons
  - Subseries VII.D.1. Editor Charles Osborne: Correspondence Files, 1975-1978; 0.8 Linear feet in 2 records cartons
    Charles Osborne first appears in Time Inc. department head lists in 1968 as an editor for Time-Life Books. He continues to work for Time-Life Books until at least 1978 when he begins working as an editor for television books in the special projects division of Time-Life Films. Near the end of 1978, Osborne leaves Time-Life Films and returns to Time-Life Books. After 1978, Osborne no longer appears in department head lists.
    The Editor Charles Osborne Correspondence Files cover the period of 1975 to 1978. The correspondence included in this subseries discuss materials to prepare, vacations, photographs, book covers, staffing, meetings, agreements, contact information, copyright, sale, project statuses, book descriptions, Library of Congress catalog numbers, and magazine subscriptions.
    - Chronological Files, 1975-1978 (Offsite-box 3382, Folder 3-14)
    - Chronological Files [RESTRICTED], 1976-1978 (Offsite-box R58)
  - Subseries VII.D.2. Production Files, 1974-1978; 5.15 Linear feet in 8 records cartons
    The Production Files cover the period of 1974 to 1978 and contain materials related to the production of books related to Time-Films. Included in this subseries are chapter drafts, notes, a Library of Congress Catalog Data Sheet, cover drafts, copyright drafts, bibliographies, book recommendations, clippings, list of picture fees, budgets, list of typist fees, invoices, list acknowledgments, lists of payments, payroll cards, promotion schedules, project due dates, agreements, picture payment cards, project reports, television show scripts, books, list of active book buyers, sales reports, list of titles in series, list of animals featured in book, production schedules, list of cash settlements, and correspondence. The correspondence discuss chapter comments, changes in manuscripts, deliveries, project updates, copyright, royalties, accounts, underwriters, payments, agreements and contracts, project proposals, proofs, production rates, transparencies, borrowing or using outside images, and promotion campaigns.
    - Fall of Eagles, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3382, Folder 15)
    - Fall of Eagles: BBC, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3382, Folder 16)
    - Fall of Eagles: BBC [RESTRICTED], 1973-1976 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Fall of Eagles: Crown Publishers, Inc., 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3382, Folder 17)
    - Fall of Eagles: Crown Publishers Inc. [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Fall of Eagles: Promo Pieces, Pictures, Publicity, 1974-1978 (Offsite-box 3382, Folder 18)
    - Fall of Eagles: Published Book, 1977 (Offsite-box 3382, Folder 19)
    - Fall of Eagles: Published Book, 1974 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 1)
    - Life Goes to War, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 2)
    - Life Goes to War: Ads/Promotion, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 3)
    - Life Goes to War: American Book, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 4)
    - Life Goes to War: Budget, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 5)
    - Life Goes to War: Comp Copies, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 6)
    - Life Goes to War: Expenses, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 7)
    - Life Goes to War: Expenses [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Life Goes to War: Flap Copy, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 8)
    - Life Goes to War: Foreign Editions, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 9)
    - Life Goes to War: Gold, Robert C. and Associates, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 10)
    - Life Goes to War: Gold, Robert C. and Associates Inc. [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Life Goes to War: Haley, Jack Jr.: Productions and Publicity, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 11)
    - Life Goes to War: Little, Brown, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 12)
    - Life Goes to War: Little, Brown [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Life Goes to War: Little, Brown: Promotion, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 13)
    - Life Goes to War: NBC Promotion, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 14)
    - Life Goes to War: Pequot Avenue Group, Inc.: Sears Library Service, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 15)
    - Life Goes to War: Permissions, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 16)
    - Life Goes to War: Permissions [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Life Goes to War: Picture Pay Cards, undated (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 17-18)
    - Life Goes to War: Pictures, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 19)
    - Life Goes to War: Pictures [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Life Goes to War: Prospectus, 1974-1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 20)
    - Life Goes to War: Reprint, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 21)
    - Life Goes to War: Schedules, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 22)
    - Life Goes to War: Staff, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 23)
    - Life Goes to War: Staff [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Life Goes to War: Television, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 24)
    - Life Goes to War: Time-Life Books, 1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 25)
    - Ten Who Dared, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 26)
    - Ten Who Dared [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Ten Who Dared: BBC, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 27)
    - Ten Who Dared: Bills, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3383, Folder 28-29)
    - Ten Who Dared: Book Orders/Comp Copies, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 1)
    - Ten Who Dared: Book Orders/Comp Copies [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Ten Who Dared: Foreign Sales, 1977 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 2)
    - Ten Who Dared: Introduction, 1976 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 3)
    - Ten Who Dared: Introduction: Edit Stages, 1976 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 4-5)
    - Ten Who Dared: Jacket/Cover/Front Matter, 1976 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 6)
    - Ten Who Dared: Little, Brown, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 7)
    - Ten Who Dared: Little, Brown [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Ten Who Dared: Mobil, 1976 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 8)
    - Ten Who Dared: Mobil [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Ten Who Dared: Pictures, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 9-10)
    - Ten Who Dared: Preface, 1976 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 11)
    - Ten Who Dared: Published Books, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 12-13)
    - Ten Who Dared: Research, 1960, 1976, undated (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 14-15)
    - Ten Who Dared: Reviews, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 16)
    - Ten Who Dared: TV, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 17)
    - A Third Testament, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 18)
    - A Third Testament: BBC, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 19)
    - A Third Testament: BBC [RESTRICTED], 1975-1976 (Offsite-box R58)
    - A Third Testament: Collins Publishers [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Offsite-box R58)
    - A Third Testament: James-Christen Associates, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 20)
    - A Third Testament: James-Christen Associates [RESTRICTED], 1975-976 (Offsite-box R59)
    - A Third Testament: Little, Brown, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 21)
    - A Third Testament: Nielsen-Ferns LTD., 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 22)
    - A Third Testament: Promo Pieces, Pictures, and Publicity, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 23)
    - A Third Testament: Published Book, 1976 (Offsite-box 3384, Folder 24)
    - A Third Testament: Raymond/Taffner Limited (Bruce Raymond Limited) [RESTRICTED], 1975-1977 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: 1974 September 26 - 1975 June 23, 1974-1975, undated (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 1-2)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Artwork, undated (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 3)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: California Board of Education, 1977 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 4)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Contract Forms [RESTRICTED], 1975-1977 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Horenstein, Sidney [RESTRICTED], 1977-1978 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: International, 1975-1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 5)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: International [RESTRICTED], 1975-1976 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: ISBN Numbers, 1975 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 6)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Logo, 1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 7)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Master Index, undated (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 8)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Masthead, 1975 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 9)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Menhelsohn vs. Vineyard Books [RESTRICTED], 1975-1979 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Production, 1975-1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 10)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Reprints, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 11)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Sales Report, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 12)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Schedule, 1975-1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 13)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Staff, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 14)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Staff [RESTRICTED], 1977-1978 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Style Points, 1977 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 15)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Time-Life Books/Time-Life Films Agreement, 1975-1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 16)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Time-Life Films: Animal Books, 1974-1985 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 17)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Titles, 1974-1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 18-19)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Tree Communications, Inc., 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 20)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Vineyard: Contract, Lease, Payments, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 21-23)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Vineyard: Contract, Lease, Payments [RESTRICTED], 1975-1976 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Vineyard Contract: Last [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Vineyard Books, Inc., 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 24)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Vineyard Books, Inc. [RESTRICTED], 1975 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Vineyard Contract: Last, 1977 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 25)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Writers, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 26)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Zoo Arrangements, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 27)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: General: Zoo Arrangements [RESTRICTED], 1975 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 1: Cats, 1975 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 28)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 1: Cats: Errata, 1976 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 29)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 1: Cats: Published Book, 1976 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 30)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 2: Monkeys and Apes, 1975 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 31)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 2: Monkeys and Apes: Errata, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 32)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 2: Monkeys and Apes: Published Books, 1976 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 33)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 3: Dangerous Sea Creatures, 1978 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 34)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 3: Dangerous Sea Creatures: Errata, 1976 (Offsite-box 3385, Folder 35)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 3: Dangerous Sea Creatures: Published Book, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 1)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 3: Dangerous Sea Creatures: Shark Chart, 1976 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 2)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 4: Elephants and Other Land Giants: Errata, 1976 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 3)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 4: Elephants and Other Land Giants: Published Books, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 4)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 4: Elephants and Other Land Giants: Reprints, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 5-6)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 5: Reptiles and Amphibians, 1975 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 7)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 5: Reptiles and Amphibians, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 8)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 5: Reptiles and Amphibians: Published Book, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 9)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 6: Birds of Sea, Shore and Stream, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 10)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 6: Birds of Sea, Shore and Stream, 1976 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 11)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 6: Birds of Sea, Shore and Stream: Reprint, 1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 12)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 7: Bears and Other Carnivores, 1976 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 13)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 7: Bears and Other Carnivores: Errata, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 14)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 7: Bears and Other Carnivores: Published Books, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 15)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 8: Aquatic Mammals, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 16)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 8: Whales and Other Sea Mammals: Errata, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 17)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 8: Whales and Other Sea Mammals: Published Book, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 18)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 9: Wild Herds [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 9: Wild Herds: Errata, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 19)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 9: Wild Herds: Published Book, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 20)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 10: Insects, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 21)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 10: Insects [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 10: Insects and Spiders: Errata, 1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 22)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 10: Insects and Spiders: Published Book, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 23)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 11: Birds of Field and Forest [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 11: Birds of Field and Forest: Published Book, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 24)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 12: Creatures of the Reef [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 12: Coral Reef: Errata, 1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 25)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 12: Life in the Coral Reef: Published Book, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 26)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 13: Beavers and Other Animals from the Pond [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 13: Beavers and Other Animals from the Pond, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 27)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 13: Beavers and Other Pond Dwellers: Errata, 1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 28)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 13: Beavers and Other Pond Dwellers: Published Book, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 29)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 14: Kangaroos and Other Animals from Down Under [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 14: Kangaroos and Other Creatures from Down Under: Published Books, 1977 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 30)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 15: Song Birds, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 31)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 15: Songbirds: Errata, 1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 32)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 15: Songbirds: Missing and Damaged Transparencies, 1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 33)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 15: Songbirds: Published Book, 1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 34)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 16: Island Life [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 16: Island Life: Published Book, 1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 35)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 17: Fish, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 36)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 17: Fish [RESTRICTED], 1977-1978 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 17: Fishes of Lakes, Rivers and Oceans: Errata, 1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 37)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 17: Fishes of Lakes, Rivers and Oceans: Published Book, 1978 (Offsite-box 3386, Folder 38)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 18: Zoos and Preserves [RESTRICTED], 1977-1978 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 18: Life in Zoos and Preserves: Errata, undated (Offsite-box 3387, Folder 1)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 18: Life in Zoos and Preserves: Published Book, 1978 (Offsite-box 3387, Folder 2)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 19: Rabbits and Other Small Mammals [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 19: Rabbits and Other Small Mammals: Published Book, 1978 (Offsite-box 3387, Folder 3)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 20: Modes of Survival [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 20: Animal Defenses: Errata, undated (Offsite-box 3387, Folder 4)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 20: Animal Defenses: Published Book, 1978 (Offsite-box 3387, Folder 5)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 21: Domestic Descendants [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. 22: Unseen Water Dwellers [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Offsite-box R59)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. Unknown: Animals Around Man, 1976 (Offsite-box 3387, Folder 6)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. Unknown: Monotremes and Marsupials: Contents, 1976 (Offsite-box 3387, Folder 7)
    - Wild, Wild World of Animals: Vol. Unknown: Parents and Offspring [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Offsite-box R59)
  - Subseries VII.D.3. Life Goes to War Copy Files, 1935-1977; 5 Linear feet in 5 records cartons
    The Life Goes to War Copy Files cover the period of 1935 to 1977. The majority of materials dated earlier than 1970 are photocopies of materials used for research. The focus of this subseries is on the research and production of Life Goes to War and mainly includes photocopies of materials used for research and chapter drafts. When the files were transferred to the archive, they were identified as copy files from the Time-Life Books editor Charles Osborne. The records themselves do not indicate if he worked with them. Many of the documents appear to have initials written on them but it is unclear who the initials belong to. The name that appears most frequently is David Scherman who was an editor working on Life Goes to War.
    Arranged by chapter.
    - Chapter 1, 1977, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 1-3)
    - Chapter 1: Allied Enemy Prep, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 1: Appeasement Politics, 1937-1939, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 1: Bloodless Conquest, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 1: Chamberlain and Conquest Stalin, 1935-1941, 1962 (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 1: China, 1937-1941, 1966, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 1: China: Mao-Chiang, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 1: China: Newsreel Wong, Natori. Miscellaneous, 1937-1938, 1957, 1972-1975 (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 1: Closed Copy, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 12-14)
    - Chapter 1: Goring-Goebbels, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 1: Hitler, 1938-1940,1970, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 16-17)
    - Chapter 1: Japanese Home Front and Prep, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 1: Mussolini, 1937-1938, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 19-20)
    - Chapter 1: Nazism-Fascism, 1938, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 21-22)
    - Chapter 1: Seeds of War, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 1: Spain, 1937-1939, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 24-26)
    - Chapter 1: Stalin, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 27)
    - Chapter 1: U.S., 1939-1940, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 28)
    - Chapter 1: U.S. Homefront, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 29)
    - Chapter 1: U.S. Reaction, Preparation, and Lack of, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 30)
    - Chapter 2, 1944, 1966, 1977, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 31-32)
    - Chapter 2: Allied Reaction to War, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 33)
    - Chapter 2: The Balkans, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 34)
    - Chapter 2: Barbarossa, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 35)
    - Chapter 2: Battle of the Atlantic, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 36-37)
    - Chapter 2: Battle of the Atlantic: Won, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 38)
    - Chapter 2: Battle of Britain, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 39)
    - Chapter 2: Battle of Britain and British Home Front, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 40)
    - Chapter 2: Belgium, Holland, Normand and Sitz Krieg, undated (Offsite-box 3407, Folder 41)
    - Chapter 2: Britain vs. Italy: Axis Reverses, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 2: China Contained, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 2: Churchill, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 2: Defeat of Poland, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 2: Dunkirk, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 2: European Reaction After Poland, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 2: Fall of France, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 2: Finland, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 2: General and Photographs, 1936-1945, 1954, 1964, 1973-1977, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 9-10)
    - Chapter 2: Goodbyes, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 2: Heds, 1977, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 2: Introduction, 1939-1941, 1977, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 13-14)
    - Chapter 2: Introduction: Photographers, 1942, 1977, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 2: Isolation vs. Intervention, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 2: Photographers, 1939-1945, 1951, 1961, 1967-1977, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 17-22)
    - Chapter 2: Production, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 2: Spread 2 and 3: Left and Right, 1939-1940, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Offsite-box 24)
    - Chapter 2: Spread 4 and 5, 1939, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 2: Spreads 7-9, 1940, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 2: US Aid, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 27)
    - Chapter 2: US First Reaction, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 28)
    - Chapter 2: US Preparation and National Defense, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 29)
    - Chapter 3, 1977 (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 30)
    - Chapter 3: Home Front: Cartoons, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 31)
    - Chapter 3: Introduction, 1941-1942, 1959, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 32)
    - Chapter 3: Miscellaneous Research, 1941, 1977, undated (Offsite-box 3408, Folder 33)
    - Chapter 3: Spreads, 1941-1945, 1977, undated (Offsite-box 3413, Folder 1-5)
    - Chapter 4, 1977 (Offsite-box 3413, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 4: Aleutians, undated (Offsite-box 3413, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 4: Anti-War Efforts, undated (Offsite-box 3413, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 4: Anzio and Italy, undated (Offsite-box 3413, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 4: Checked Copy, 1940-1945, 1966, 1977, undated (Offsite-box 3413, Folder 10-18)
    - Chapter 4: Checked Copy, 1941-1945, 1977, undated (Offsite-box 3414, Folder 1-2)